today we're going to Japan with
ceremonial grade matcha green tea
powder my wife and I honeymooned in Tokyo and
the Philippines Tokyo was off the chart it's
possibly top five places I've ever been why
is Tokyo so special I mean Japan as a whole
is super special it's so different to westernized
countries it's Ultra busy in Tokyo but everyone is
very respectful it's quiet it's calm it's relaxed
it's clean it's just an incredible place but when
the Night Comes and the entire city is filled with
neon lights blows you away you've got Godzilla or
godilla on top of a building in Tokyo Godzilla
obviously is a Kaiju I I can't recommend Tokyo
enough and we're going back soon to look at and
visit Old Japan but when you're there and you
do all the typical touristy things that we all
do one of the things is green tea and matcha is
the number one name in green tea it's green tea
is an umbrella term and then matcha is part of
that there are different grades of matcha powder
and they all are used in different situations so
this one we have here is ceremonial grade this
come this has come straight from Japan itself so
this is this is a reasonably good matcha powder
you can spend thousands on matcha powder now
it's a delicate flavor we don't want to turn
this into a super fatty ice cream we're going
to turn this into an ultra lowfat gelato we're
going down to 6% fat which is you know the the
lowest recommended fat range for a gelato in
traditional terms you can go down to zero fat
gelato but then you're not creating gelato you're
creating something different that aside what are
we going to need to make our Japanese ceremonial
matcha gelato well for this you are going to need
30 G of organic ceremonial matcher powder 500
G of 2% milk 125 G of 33% whipping cream 30
G of skin milk powder 120 g of sugar and 40 G
of dextrose we're going to add a stabilizer to
this one a couple of notes we're using dextrose
cuz it's much less sweet than standard sugar so
we can get more of that matcha flavor to come
through it also helps us adjust the freezing
point of this we're using just enough cream to
bring the fat percentage up to 6% if you don't
want to add cream at all you're going to need to
increase your stabilizer amount and potentially
add something else now matcha is pretty much all
fiber that that is what it is it's all carbs there
are lots of different carbohydrates out in the
world this is basically a plant that is milled
down into this ultra fine powder be because it's
fiber it can help and boost our overrun levels
which is excellent but we need to be careful not
to overpower the flavor of this with other things
so less chitchat let's get on with it we are
simply going to add all our ingredients into
the pan so in goes our 500 G of 2% milk our 125
G of whipping cream 40 G of dextrose 120 g of
sugar we're going to keep 10 G back so let's put
110 G in into that 10 G we're going to put in
our guar gum because it's cold processed we're
not super heating this because you don't want
that Dairy flavor or at least overheated Dairy
flavor to affect our matcher so in that goes
and finally our entire 30 G of ceremonial matcha
powder you don't have to use ceremonial matcha
powder where are the scissors you can use
any matcha powder you can use the cheapest
matchup powder you can find on Amazon that
is fine like that lovely little tin going to
keep that so we've got everything apart from
our skin milk powder in here which is 30 G
like that and we are just going to gently
warm this up on the hob to make sure all of
our ingredients are dissolved and emulsified
together to create a lovely homogeneous blend
of match deliciousness as you start to heat the
base up it will come become super intense green
as it all starts to dissolve together we're
going to bring this up just to steam point so
somewhere around 55 60° centigrade and then
we'll take it off the heat right we've just
got up to 60 Centigrade don't need to go any
higher G gum is a cold process stabilizer so
we don't need to go super high we are going to
put this in a container and let it cool down
couple of notes super intense green color from
the matcha matcha powder is designed to be saved
so it goes through a fine Sie we're going to Sie
this after after it cools down to take out any
impurities we want this super clean super smooth
so chill it down in the fridge if you can do it
overnight or even 24 hours even better because
that will boost that flavor within the dairy and
that's exactly what we want so I will come back
when this is completely chilled down right it's
been in the fridge for a couple of days we're
going to run this through a sa and get this
this as smooth as we can so yeah nice that
exactly what I want I'm not going to push
those little bits through I'm just going to leave
them in there PR chilling let's get this in the
machine and get it churning something we want
to try and Achieve with this is a large amount
of overun because the flavor is pretty bold and
Punchy there's a lot of match powder 30 R in this
mix so we want as much overrun as we can sensibly
get in a home machine because matcha is just fiber
I'm hoping that we can achieve a fair amount so
let's get this turnning and I'm going to tidy
up let's try something new shall we
straight out of machine super strong flavor matcha
most matcha ice creams or gelato are so weak in
flavor that they're kind of ACH into a matcha
latte kind of flavor which defeats the point
of matcha itself which is super strong in taste we
went to quite a few different sushi restaurants in
Tokyo and you get matcha on the side where you're
sat generally it's free and I mean it's not super
high quality but it doesn't make any difference
it's the taste you there's hot water on tap you
take your spoonful of match powder put it in the
little cup that is supplied for you and make it up
there and then super strong there's no inclusion
of milk it's a green tea so it's you know supposed
to be had just with water but drink it how you
like but what we've done here I had to make an
adjustment this is actually my second batch first
batch didn't get basically any overrun and that is
the the fiber content I think this is the fiber
content combined with the other ingredients made
it too thick made it too viscous to churn and get
the correct amount of overun so I've redone the
recipe I will put in the description the actual
new recipe it's basically the same but has more
milk but what we've got here is a super intense
matcha ice cream Ultra smooth you get nothing but
matcha flavor through there super super nice the
cream helps to smooth that bitterness of matcha
out it can be quite bitter and the stronger
you get the worse it gets super delicious
really really nice such a strong flavor you don't
need a full scoop we had the quinel there that's
a perfect serving size for this cuz it's such
an intense flavor so if you want to make this
amazing matcha gelato follow the recipe in the
description not the one at the early part of the
video I'll probably change the one in the video
as well cuz I I don't want you to get this wrong
and smaller portion size after a big heavy meal
you're going to love this one if you like green
tea if you don't give it a try you never know
whether you're going to like something new or
not unless you try it anyway thanks very much for
watching don't forget to like And subscribe next
week we've got a ninja creamy coffee special
and after that I'm doing molted mini egg ice
cream just like a Calgary ice screamery that we
frequent sometimes so if you don't want to miss
out make sure to like subscribe comment all of
that kind of jazz and I'll see you next time